<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rivals Academy Lectures</title><link>https://rivals.academy/lectures</link><description>Recent content in Rivals Academy Lectures</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://rivals.academy/tags/clairen/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Clairen Axmos Drop Up Special</title><link>https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-axmos-drop-upspecial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-axmos-drop-upspecial/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="how-to" class="heading">
How To&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: How To"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;how-to&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For a deep dive into Fastfall Storage and Axmos Drops, visit my &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1tZLo8hJ38uXZYSS9K4WB-nsnYTeoeqYEr-IBYQ-R_XE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in-depth guide&lt;/a>. Here is the basic explanation of how to Axmos Drop with Clairen&amp;rsquo;s Up Special:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Perform a platform drop&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Airdodge and waveland back onto the platform ASAP to “store” your platdrop timer value&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hit your opponent with Up Special&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hold down immediately - this is not a timed input, simply hold down - your attack should automatically fastfall when the stored platdrop timer ends&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Clairen’s Axmos Drop prevents her Up Special from rising when performed from a platform. In fact, while using the standard version of this technique it is not possible to begin the second part of Up Special at all, with Clairen landing immediately after the third hit ends. It is possible to gain access to the full attack still by first running off the platform to become airborne before beginning the attack, with this allowing you to Axmos Drop whilst still altering your momentum through delaying the second slash input.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-axmos-drop-upspecial/demo.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-axmos-drop-upspecial/demo.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-axmos-drop-upspecial/demo.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;h2 id="application" class="heading">
Application&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: Application"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;application&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Axmos Drop changes the way you can use Clairen’s Up Special on platforms, making the attack a far more aggressive tool. This is not dissimilar to using the attack as a poke tool on certain stages where it is possible to travel seamlessly from ground to platform. One clear distinction with the Axmos Drop variation from this is that it allows Clairen to begin a combo against opponents beside her as well as against those directly beneath her however. Due to the size of the first hitbox it is possible to hit a number of characters while they are standing under Clairen, with this working on all characters from standard platform height with the exception of Sylvanos, Maypul, Ori and Orcane. Against all other characters, the spacing required for this is slightly more than a full character length away from Clairen.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-axmos-drop-upspecial/hit-below.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-axmos-drop-upspecial/hit-below.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-axmos-drop-upspecial/hit-below.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>This large threat zone makes it possible to drag these characters upwards to the platform from some distance away before you attempt your combo extension. The spacing of this also makes it a relatively safe distance against a handful of recoveries too, leading to this being an unpredictable edgeguarding option that’s been adopted by a few notable players.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s worth noting that the combo possibilities that exist are only practical due to the low pratfall landing lag on the first part of Up Special, which allows you to act only 11 frames after landing. By being actionable so soon after dragging her opponent upwards, Clairen is provided with multiple follow-up opportunities on poor DI. The most popular of these is a Tipper Up Strong, with the relatively high hitstun of the attack allowing this to connect as characters fall back towards Clairen.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-axmos-drop-upspecial/upstrong.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-axmos-drop-upspecial/upstrong.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-axmos-drop-upspecial/upstrong.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>Later experimentation saw the Axmos Drop being used to drag opponents up from below Clairen into her other Strong attacks as well, however this use of Up Special keeps your opponent close enough that there are other combo possibilities to consider outside of this. If you are aiming for a flashy way to close a stock however, the tweets linked throughout this guide may serve as a quick reference of how members of the community have used the technique over time.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-axmos-drop-upspecial/fstrong.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-axmos-drop-upspecial/fstrong.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-axmos-drop-upspecial/fstrong.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>It’s clear that this is the Axmos Drop that the community has embraced the most since it was discovered. That being said, there are still weaknesses to the technique. Due to the very nature of this attack being multi-hit, the Up Special could be considered relatively easy to react to, with it allowing an opportunity for the opponent to correct their DI. This is not even taking into account the regular process of storing your fast-fall telegraphing your option to your opponent. For these reasons this technique cannot be relied on to close stocks with absolute certainty, and even with its popularity amongst dedicated Clairen players it is still regarded as a niche option even years after its discovery.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Clairen Up Special Edgecancel</title><link>https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-upspecial-edgecancel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-upspecial-edgecancel/</guid><description>&lt;p>Clairen&amp;rsquo;s Up Special gives her a horizontal momentum boost after the second hit. Combined with her above average air acceleration, this means she’s one of the best characters at edgecancelling her recovery. This is valuable as being able to edgecancel out of your pratfall can provide you with some unique recovery mixups, such as wavelanding back onto the stage or drifting back and approaching the ledge a second time with your resources refreshed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this guide we will cover how to edgecancel your recovery from various heights as you approach the stage. For all variations of shown you will need to drift forward until the end of the second hit. Inputs are shown in each clip if you’re struggling, so use these as a quick reference as you attempt these recoveries for yourself. Hitting the opponent with your Up Special will slightly alter the timing, however each example will still be possible to perform.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="off-the-wall" class="heading">
Off the Wall&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: Off the Wall"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;off-the-wall&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The safest way to edgecancel Up Special is to avoid riding the wall and using both hits above stage height so that you end up decently far in from the edge. You can then use the horizontal boost backwards with much less risk of an SD. You build up enough momentum as you drift back that you&amp;rsquo;ll slide slightly as you land, so don&amp;rsquo;t worry if you don&amp;rsquo;t position yourself perfectly for these.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-upspecial-edgecancel/off-the-wall.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-upspecial-edgecancel/off-the-wall.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-upspecial-edgecancel/off-the-wall.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;h2 id="wallride" class="heading">
Wallride&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: Wallride"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;wallride&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Edgecancelling after a wallride is slightly riskier, but it&amp;rsquo;s a very common position to be in when recovering so this variant might be the most useful one to master. It is usually performed by using both hits above stage height after riding up the wall, and leaving the stick in a neutral position during the horizontal boost window before immediately drifting back.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-upspecial-edgecancel/wallride.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-upspecial-edgecancel/wallride.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-upspecial-edgecancel/wallride.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;h2 id="from-ledge" class="heading">
From Ledge&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: From Ledge"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;from-ledge&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you begin your Up Special from higher up, the method is very similar to doing a wallride. Avoid the horizontal boost and drift backwards, however. You will often need to start drifting back later than with the wallride variant.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-upspecial-edgecancel/from-ledge.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-upspecial-edgecancel/from-ledge.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-upspecial-edgecancel/from-ledge.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>Note: performing the second hit of your Up Special at this height may leave you vulnerable as you drift back towards the ledge, so keep in mind your opponent’s position when using this variation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="perfectly-spaced" class="heading">
Perfectly Spaced&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: Perfectly Spaced"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;perfectly-spaced&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This final variant is the hardest to pull off by far, but arguably the safest due to the minimal airtime above the ledge making it difficult to counter. Use only the final hit above stage height, then use the horizontal boost inwards before drifting back.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-upspecial-edgecancel/perfectly-spaced.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-upspecial-edgecancel/perfectly-spaced.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/clairen-upspecial-edgecancel/perfectly-spaced.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>Once you&amp;rsquo;ve started mastering this technique, there&amp;rsquo;s no need to follow these guidelines anymore. The ultimate goal is to be able to pull it off freely, from any position, at any time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Platboost &amp; Ledgeboost</title><link>https://rivals.academy/lectures/platboost-and-ledgeboost/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rivals.academy/lectures/platboost-and-ledgeboost/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-boosting" class="heading">
What is Boosting?&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: What is Boosting?"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;what-is-boosting&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When characters leave a platform, they will carry some amount of speed with them into the air depending on their status and properties. Characters who are faster on the ground than in the air have their speed capped upon leaving mostly due to their &amp;ldquo;Max Horizontal Jump Speed&amp;rdquo; stat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is where &lt;strong>boosting&lt;/strong> comes in, a catch-all term for techniques involving leaving a platform during initial dash that enables certain characters to bypass those speed caps. This can be used to enable highly effective burst movement around platforms, shown below.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/platboost-and-ledgeboost/showcase.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/platboost-and-ledgeboost/showcase.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/platboost-and-ledgeboost/showcase.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;h3 id="techniques" class="heading">
Techniques&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: Techniques"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;techniques&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Boosting is split up into four techniques: platboost, ledgeboost, platmoost, and ledgemoost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first two subcategories of these techniques are &lt;strong>platboosting&lt;/strong> vs. &lt;strong>ledgeboosting&lt;/strong>. These refer to whether you leave the platform by dropping through with a platform drop (&lt;strong>platboost&lt;/strong>) or by dashing off the edge (&lt;strong>ledgeboost&lt;/strong>) during your initial dash. Note that the duration of initial dashes varies across the cast from 8 to 16 frames, with the longer dashes giving you a larger window for performing the tech. These techniques will &lt;em>not&lt;/em> work if you enter the run animation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second distinction is &lt;strong>boosting&lt;/strong> vs. &lt;strong>moosting&lt;/strong>. &lt;strong>Boost&lt;/strong> refers to performing the tech via an initial dash. &lt;strong>Moost&lt;/strong> refers to performing the tech via a moonwalk, which has similar behavior to initial dash, but at max speed is 20% faster than initial dash for all characters (and you’ll be traveling backwards).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cast-viability" class="heading">
Cast Viability&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: Cast Viability"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;cast-viability&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With that explanation out of the way, here is my qualitative summary of the effectiveness of these techniques across the cast. Characters that stand to benefit from learning this tech (in my opinion) are bolded.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="cast-comparison.png" alt="Table summarizing the viability of Platboost, Ledgeboost, Platmoost, and Ledgemoost across the cast">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This tech can be used to enhance a variety of options: going deep for edgeguards, faster movement for platdrop aerials, traveling across platforms, and more. Go try it out!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>