<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>advanced on Rivals of Aether Academy</title><link>https://rivals.academy/tags/advanced/</link><description>Recent content in advanced on Rivals of Aether Academy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://rivals.academy/tags/advanced/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>All About Ori Dair</title><link>https://rivals.academy/guides/all-about-ori-dair/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rivals.academy/guides/all-about-ori-dair/</guid><description>Ori Dair on the surface seems quite linear, but with clever usage of hitfalling and calculated risk, it can lead into some dangerous confirms and net you some early and satisfying kills.
Hitfall Kills Onstage Copied link! While onstage, you have access to strong attacks, and coupled with Dair&amp;rsquo;s hefty hitstun, you have access to stable setups into your strongs.
Dair &amp;gt; Fstrong Copied link! While many of Ori&amp;rsquo;s kill setups require DI reads or guessing, Dair &amp;gt; Fstrong can be done on reaction.</description></item><item><title>Invincible Ledgedash</title><link>https://rivals.academy/guides/invincible-ledgedash/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rivals.academy/guides/invincible-ledgedash/</guid><description>Why Ledgedash? Copied link! First, what is a ledgedash? Ledgedashing is teching the corner of the stage wall after a hit and quickly wavelanding onto stage while you still have invincibility. Ledgedashing can be a useful tool for recovery and a possible reversal when being edgeguarded, and we&amp;rsquo;ve seen it become increasingly prominent in Rivals&amp;rsquo; meta over the past few years.
Download the WEBM or MP4 video. How To Copied link!</description></item><item><title>Niche Applications of Clone</title><link>https://rivals.academy/guides/niche-applications-of-clone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rivals.academy/guides/niche-applications-of-clone/</guid><description>These situational tactics are meant for players who are already proficient at using Forsburn&amp;rsquo;s clone, so if you have not already learned to regularly implement cloning for recovery, stalling in the air, and as an edgeguarding tool, then I would recommend that you master those techniques before learning these. With that being said, let&amp;rsquo;s begin!
Clone &amp;gt; Up Strong Copied link! Up Strong 2 is Forsburn&amp;rsquo;s strongest grounded move, but landing it for a kill can be inconsistent at times.</description></item><item><title>The Pityflip</title><link>https://rivals.academy/guides/the-pityflip/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rivals.academy/guides/the-pityflip/</guid><description>My flip is, at its purest, just a wavebounce dspecial cancelled into the flip. Alongside the flashy tricks, it’s main purposes are movement and recovery mix ups. Wavebouncing/reversing dspecial alone is a great way to mix up your landings and platform movement, but the flip makes you that much more mobile and slippery (and cool).
How To Copied link! The inputs consist firstly of a Down Special followed by a press of the dodge button to cancel into a flip, but what matters the most is how you turn yourself around with the analog stick.</description></item></channel></rss>