<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rivals Academy Lectures</title><link>https://rivals.academy/lectures</link><description>Recent content in Rivals Academy Lectures</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://rivals.academy/tags/shovel-knight/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Economics 101</title><link>https://rivals.academy/lectures/economics-101/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rivals.academy/lectures/economics-101/</guid><description>&lt;p>Shovel Knight’s passive ability allows him to create collectable gems on hitting an opponent. This amount will always be &lt;strong>17 times&lt;/strong> the amount of damage that is dealt, with the gems that spawn randomly selected to make up the sum of this value. The gems are collectable for 240-260 frames each, with larger value gems fading away later than smaller valued gems.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="chesters-shop" class="heading">
Chester&amp;rsquo;s Shop&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: Chester&amp;rsquo;s Shop"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;chesters-shop&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Once you amass enough gems you’ll be able to spend it using Shovel Knight’s taunt, summoning Chester and allowing you to browse the various relics and armors he has on offer. The relics will replace your neutral special with a new attack and the armors grant you new abilities or stats.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A significant feature of the shop is that you are able to quickly purchase relics and armors using the right stick!&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Left&lt;/strong> will purchase the &lt;strong>War Horn&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Up&lt;/strong> will purchase the &lt;strong>Mobile Gear&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Down&lt;/strong> will purchase &lt;strong>Dynamo Mail&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Right&lt;/strong> will purchase &lt;strong>Mail of Momentum&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If you would like to quick-buy &lt;strong>Ghost Gloves&lt;/strong>, simply &lt;strong>press A&lt;/strong> upon entering Chester&amp;rsquo;s shop, as the cursor always begins on them.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="value-and-cost" class="heading">
Value and Cost&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: Value and Cost"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;value-and-cost&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Since this currency system is such an important part of Shovel Knight’s playstyle, with the relics and armours greatly impacting how you will play each game, it’s important to understand the values of each gem and item. The below image shows the value of each gem and item, as well as the values for an Up Strong Rock, Down Special&amp;rsquo;s Treasure Pile, and the Golden Troupple Fish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="values.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is one more source of gems however…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="money-bags.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On dying, Shovel Knight will lose 25% of his total savings, with this amount being split between three different valued bags. One bag will always contain half of this amount, a second bag will contain a third and the final bag will contain only a sixth of the total spawned on death. These bags are collectable for a total of 600 frames, however after 300 frames they can be nabbed up by your opponent, so make sure to recover your lost goods before they’re snatched up! As there are three different sized bags that can spawn, prioritize those larger bags and start saving towards your next big purchase!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s all for today, class dismissed!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SK Dstrong Utility &amp; Movement</title><link>https://rivals.academy/lectures/sk-dstrong-utility-and-movement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rivals.academy/lectures/sk-dstrong-utility-and-movement/</guid><description>&lt;p>Although Shovel Knight’s Down Strong is weaker in terms of knockback when compared to his other strong attacks, the move has a few niche movement options that are important to learn if you want to bring out the full potential of the move.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="horizontal-range" class="heading">
Horizontal Range&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: Horizontal Range"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;horizontal-range&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Down Strong allows you to cover a range of distances by preserving some of your momentum as you start the move, as well as allowing you to drift slightly in either direction during your rise into the air. The below clip demonstrates how different methods of movement allow you to manipulate the horizontal distance of your leap. Mail of Momentum (MoM) changes the properties of your wavedash and run turnaround significantly, having it equipped will change how you can use the move to your advantage.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/sk-dstrong-utility-and-movement/horizontal.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/sk-dstrong-utility-and-movement/horizontal.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/sk-dstrong-utility-and-movement/horizontal.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;h2 id="vertical-boost" class="heading">
Vertical Boost&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: Vertical Boost"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;vertical-boost&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Shovel Knight’s vertical leap can be increased by holding up during Down Strong’s startup. If you are holding up on the 6th frame of startup you’ll be boosted upwards slightly, allowing you to land on standard height platforms from the stage floor. Although a slightly slower kill option than Up Strong from directly beneath a platform, this option is relevant on almost every stage in the game and can cover a wider area more reliably if you are approaching from a short distance away. In combination with some of the longer distance leaps at your disposal you can use this as a powerful aerial approach, with the strong landing hitboxes becoming active from frame 18 onwards.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/sk-dstrong-utility-and-movement/vertical-boost.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/sk-dstrong-utility-and-movement/vertical-boost.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/sk-dstrong-utility-and-movement/vertical-boost.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;h3 id="charge-boost" class="heading">
Charge Boost&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: Charge Boost"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;charge-boost&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Charging Down Strong will increase Shovel Knight’s height for 1 extra frame before his vertical position is locked in. Although not terribly notable, in combination with a boosted jump this allows you to reach the platforms on Abyssal Gates from the ground. The charge window begins on frame 17 of the attack, with only 1 frame of charge is required to increase the height. Shovel Knight will hover at this height during the full duration of the charge window (maximum of 60 frames). During the charge window you also gain the ability to also alter your horizontal position slightly during the charge by inputting left or right.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/sk-dstrong-utility-and-movement/vertical-boost-charge.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/sk-dstrong-utility-and-movement/vertical-boost-charge.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/sk-dstrong-utility-and-movement/vertical-boost-charge.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;h3 id="dynamo-mail" class="heading">
Dynamo Mail&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: Dynamo Mail"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;dynamo-mail&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Dynamo Mail allows Shovel Knight to perform any of his strong attacks in the air after a successful Down Air, providing him an aura which lasts for 600 frames, but is removed on hit. Combined with Down Strong’s vertical leap, this provides Shovel Knight the ability to super-jump with the attack when buffered during the jump-squat frames. You’ll notice your peak height will increase on either a short hop or full hop, with the full hop variation launching you much higher into the air. This can allow Shovel Knight to threaten even the highest platforms from a grounded position, impacting your attack options in neutral, the amount of space you can cover against a recovering opponent or even as a tech chase option.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/sk-dstrong-utility-and-movement/dynamo.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/sk-dstrong-utility-and-movement/dynamo.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/sk-dstrong-utility-and-movement/dynamo.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>You are also able to use the upwards boost you can gain during startup in combination with a super-jump Down Strong, meaning that while Dynamo Mail is equipped you have access to 6 different variations of Down Strong, each with a unique jump height. The below clip shows off the peak heights of each, with a detailed spreadsheet which records what variations can be used from the ground to quickly reach any platform in the game can be found &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1qXCdb3DmMhVWXIrnwwBtX0DfPguaT7rN3sXTJ5StybI" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/sk-dstrong-utility-and-movement/comparison.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/sk-dstrong-utility-and-movement/comparison.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/sk-dstrong-utility-and-movement/comparison.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>If you would like a more in-depth look at the applications of this technique I recommend checking it out and getting into practice mode to see for yourself.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>