<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>intermediate on Rivals of Aether Academy</title><link>https://rivals.academy/tags/intermediate/</link><description>Recent content in intermediate on Rivals of Aether Academy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://rivals.academy/tags/intermediate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Shine > Up Strong</title><link>https://rivals.academy/lectures/shine-upstrong/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rivals.academy/lectures/shine-upstrong/</guid><description>Zetterburn&amp;rsquo;s Shine &amp;gt; Up Strong is one of the strongest kill options in the game as it is almost always applicable for a parry punish and is a follow up off of a frame 2 move (Shine) that can also be used to whiff punish effectively. Performed correctly, it&amp;rsquo;s a true confirm on the entire cast well into Up Strong kill %.
Download the WEBM or MP4 video. How To Copied link!</description></item><item><title>SK Dstrong Utility &amp; Movement</title><link>https://rivals.academy/lectures/sk-dstrong-utility-and-movement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rivals.academy/lectures/sk-dstrong-utility-and-movement/</guid><description>Although Shovel Knight’s Down Strong is weaker in terms of knockback when compared to his other strong attacks, the move has a few niche movement options that are important to learn if you want to bring out the full potential of the move.
Horzontal Range Copied link! Down Strong allows you to cover a range of distances by preserving some of your momentum as you start the move, as well as allowing you to drift slightly in either direction during your rise into the air.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Ranno Up Air 1</title><link>https://rivals.academy/lectures/understanding-ranno-upair1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rivals.academy/lectures/understanding-ranno-upair1/</guid><description>There are a lot of misconceptions about whether this move is true in certain combos or not, and I&amp;rsquo;m here to clear them all up right here in this post! Ranno&amp;rsquo;s Up Air 1 is a unique move in that it applies a set amount of knockback and hitstun. This allows the move to function the same whether the enemy is at 0% or 200%. Knowing this, let&amp;rsquo;s look at what scenarios will allow us to reliably combo this hitbox into other moves.</description></item></channel></rss>