<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rivals Academy Lectures</title><link>https://rivals.academy/lectures</link><description>Recent content in Rivals Academy Lectures</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://rivals.academy/tags/forsburn/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Niche Applications of Clone</title><link>https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/</guid><description>&lt;p>These situational tactics are meant for players who are already proficient at using Forsburn&amp;rsquo;s clone, so if you have not already learned to regularly implement cloning for recovery, stalling in the air, and as an edgeguarding tool, then I would recommend that you master those techniques before learning these. With that being said, let&amp;rsquo;s begin!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="clone--up-strong" class="heading">
Clone &amp;gt; Up Strong&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: Clone &amp;gt; Up Strong"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;clone--up-strong&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Up Strong 2 is Forsburn&amp;rsquo;s strongest grounded move, but landing it for a kill can be inconsistent at times. Loathe though I am to admit it, there is some truth to the common Forsburn joke “Upcape is RNG” since in most cases the opponent can easily fall out of the first hit of Up Strong by DIing in front of Forsburn (away from the dagger). However, this Clone &amp;gt; Up Strong setup is fairly effective at mixing up the opponent&amp;rsquo;s DI to make the second hit of Up Strong connect. Here is the setup in action:&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/clone-upstrong.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/clone-upstrong.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/clone-upstrong.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>The key to this setup is allowing the clone to move to the other side of your opponent and then popping the opponent towards yourself. Usually when I execute this setup, it&amp;rsquo;s after I have hit the opponent to the edge and they&amp;rsquo;re coming back onstage. When the clone hits them, they&amp;rsquo;re almost always holding in to some degree because they want to get onstage/closer to center stage — if you are facing your opponent with Up Strong then this means they will conveniently be DIing &lt;em>towards&lt;/em> the dagger as shown from the DI lines here:&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/clone-upstrong-slow-di.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/clone-upstrong-slow-di.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/clone-upstrong-slow-di.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>This DI mixup is most effective near the edge when the opponent wants to get back onstage. However, even in the middle of the stage this setup is still difficult to DI correctly since the opponent often isn&amp;rsquo;t prepared to correctly DI both the clone &lt;em>and&lt;/em> the Up Strong. Additionally, the first/back hitbox of Upcape is a true link into the dagger hit so if you&amp;rsquo;re fortunate enough for the clone pop to send the opponent into that hitbox then you&amp;rsquo;ve got an easy confirm.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/clone-upstrong-2.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/clone-upstrong-2.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/clone-upstrong-2.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>This is one of my favorite kill setups and I use it quite a bit due to all the reasons listed above. It takes some experimentation to get under your belt, but is fairly easy to execute once learned and is very rewarding at low risk of overextending. Upcape may be RNG (personally I still don&amp;rsquo;t buy it), but this setup definitely helps to load it in your favor.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="clone-walling" class="heading">
Clone Walling&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: Clone Walling"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;clone-walling&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m sure that most Forsburns do this inadvertently at times, but clone walling is something that I have implemented in my play against certain characters that like to mindlessly throw out or approach with projectiles. Clone walling is simply cloning away from your opponent (so the clone is closer to your opponent) and then running in behind it with a move. If you know that the opponent likes to throw out projectiles willy nilly, this is a great way to approach them with relative safety and catch them by surprise or catch them in their endlag.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/clone-walling.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/clone-walling.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/clone-walling.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>In this clip, Ranno began the game by charging needles and fired them when he saw me approaching. With clone walling, however, I was able to catch him by surprise and approach unhindered by the projectiles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This tech won&amp;rsquo;t do your taxes for you, and it&amp;rsquo;s not going to work consistently once your opponent figures out what you&amp;rsquo;re doing, but in a game where each neutral win can lead to a precious combo or stock, this is a great mixup from simply parrying the projectile that can get you that extra neutral win. Below is a particularly deceptive example of this tech — this one worked well because the clone spawned behind my smoke, so I had an additional element of surprise when clone walling in this situation, and it got me the stock.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/clone-walling-smoke.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/clone-walling-smoke.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/clone-walling-smoke.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>Projectiles this works against:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Zetterburn&amp;rsquo;s fireball&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Absa&amp;rsquo;s Ftilt2&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Elliana&amp;rsquo;s missiles&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ori&amp;rsquo;s light orb&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ranno&amp;rsquo;s needles&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Clone walling can also be used defensively against Shovel Knight&amp;rsquo;s SideB and Wrastor&amp;rsquo;s DownB since they have hit detection and stop as soon as they hit something. In both of these cases, it&amp;rsquo;s fairly difficult to convert the clone wall into a neutral win, but it at least prevents you from getting hit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note: Kragg&amp;rsquo;s rock is not on the list above because it stays active until it touches the ground after hitting the clone. Clone walling can stop the rock from hitting you on the initial throw, but be careful about running in directly behind the clone lest you get hit while the rock is still falling.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="clone-tech-chasing" class="heading">
Clone Tech Chasing&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: Clone Tech Chasing"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;clone-tech-chasing&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re like me and have an average (at best) reaction time and consistently tech chasing is difficult, then this technique is for you. Forsburn has a lot of bread and butter combos to get the opponent from low to mid percents, but the opponent will typically start getting more chances to DI out and tech to escape your combos as they get to mid percents. Since the clone&amp;rsquo;s AI is programmed to always follow the opponent (unless you&amp;rsquo;re a maniac and press the Special button again), it has an essentially perfect reaction time and can do the tech chasing for you:&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/clone-tech-chase.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/clone-tech-chase.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/clone-tech-chase.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>In this case the clone didn&amp;rsquo;t have to move since the opponent rolled in, but it&amp;rsquo;s pretty easy to see that the clone would&amp;rsquo;ve been able to chase on any DI and tech option for a reliable follow-up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes the opponent will be able to DI hard out and escape the combo if they have enough room on the stage, but the clone charging at them will still help you press your advantage state despite not having a guaranteed follow-up.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/clone-tech-chase-2.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/clone-tech-chase-2.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/clone-tech-chase-2.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>Note: This technique should only be used at mid percents. At low percents, you should be going for different combo options and likely won&amp;rsquo;t have time to get the clone out mid-combo. At high percents, the opponent will be sent offstage or too far away for the clone to be meaningful.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="boosted-clone" class="heading">
Boosted Clone&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: Boosted Clone"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;boosted-clone&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As we all know, ledgeboosting is an essential movement option for Forsburn. The extra speed gained from ledgeboosting as opposed to simply running or wavedashing is very significant. Giving this boost to your clones by spawning them right next to the edge of a platform so that they boost off is a nice way to give a slight mixup to what is ordinarily a rather straightforward AI.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/boosted-clone-runoff.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/boosted-clone-runoff.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/boosted-clone-runoff.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>Many platforms have a short enough width that your clones will ledgeboost automatically, but learning to space your clones when on platforms so that they ledgeboost is a good habit to get into to give your opponents as little time to react as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, if the opponent is detected to be higher on the stage than the clone, it will perform a ledgeboosted jump.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/boosted-clone-jump.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/boosted-clone-jump.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/boosted-clone-jump.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>Making your clone extra speedy in this way will help keep your opponent on their toes because it looks more life-like and it gives them less time to react than a regular clone running along the ground. See non-boosted clone for comparison:&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/non-boosted-clone.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/non-boosted-clone.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/niche-applications-of-clone/non-boosted-clone.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>In my opinion, clone is very underutilized by a lot of players so hopefully these four clone tricks will help you up your clone game or even come up with your own applications for Forsburn&amp;rsquo;s trickiest move!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Platboost &amp; Ledgeboost</title><link>https://rivals.academy/lectures/platboost-and-ledgeboost/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rivals.academy/lectures/platboost-and-ledgeboost/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-boosting" class="heading">
What is Boosting?&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: What is Boosting?"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;what-is-boosting&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When characters leave a platform, they will carry some amount of speed with them into the air depending on their status and properties. Characters who are faster on the ground than in the air have their speed capped upon leaving mostly due to their &amp;ldquo;Max Horizontal Jump Speed&amp;rdquo; stat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is where &lt;strong>boosting&lt;/strong> comes in, a catch-all term for techniques involving leaving a platform during initial dash that enables certain characters to bypass those speed caps. This can be used to enable highly effective burst movement around platforms, shown below.&lt;/p>
&lt;video controls loop muted preload>
&lt;source src="https://rivals.academy/lectures/platboost-and-ledgeboost/showcase.mp4" type="video/mp4">
Download the
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/platboost-and-ledgeboost/showcase.webm">WEBM&lt;/a>
or
&lt;a href="https://rivals.academy/lectures/platboost-and-ledgeboost/showcase.mp4">MP4&lt;/a>
video.
&lt;/video>
&lt;h3 id="techniques" class="heading">
Techniques&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: Techniques"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;techniques&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Boosting is split up into four techniques: platboost, ledgeboost, platmoost, and ledgemoost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first two subcategories of these techniques are &lt;strong>platboosting&lt;/strong> vs. &lt;strong>ledgeboosting&lt;/strong>. These refer to whether you leave the platform by dropping through with a platform drop (&lt;strong>platboost&lt;/strong>) or by dashing off the edge (&lt;strong>ledgeboost&lt;/strong>) during your initial dash. Note that the duration of initial dashes varies across the cast from 8 to 16 frames, with the longer dashes giving you a larger window for performing the tech. These techniques will &lt;em>not&lt;/em> work if you enter the run animation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second distinction is &lt;strong>boosting&lt;/strong> vs. &lt;strong>moosting&lt;/strong>. &lt;strong>Boost&lt;/strong> refers to performing the tech via an initial dash. &lt;strong>Moost&lt;/strong> refers to performing the tech via a moonwalk, which has similar behavior to initial dash, but at max speed is 20% faster than initial dash for all characters (and you’ll be traveling backwards).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cast-viability" class="heading">
Cast Viability&lt;button class="heading-link"
title="Copy link"
aria-label="Copy link to this section: Cast Viability"
onclick="copyHeadingLink(&amp;#34;cast-viability&amp;#34;)">
&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">&lt;path d="M224 0c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V288c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V64c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H224zM64 160c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64V448c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H288c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V384H288v64H64V224h64V160H64z"/>&lt;/svg>
&lt;/button>
&lt;span class="copied">Copied link!&lt;/span>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With that explanation out of the way, here is my qualitative summary of the effectiveness of these techniques across the cast. Characters that stand to benefit from learning this tech (in my opinion) are bolded.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="cast-comparison.png" alt="Table summarizing the viability of Platboost, Ledgeboost, Platmoost, and Ledgemoost across the cast">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This tech can be used to enhance a variety of options: going deep for edgeguards, faster movement for platdrop aerials, traveling across platforms, and more. Go try it out!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>